<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Marcos Maso Blog</title>
    <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Marcos Maso Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 20:08:28 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>ML in optical networks</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/sgd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/sgd/</guid>
      <description>Development
Start: 08/2022.
End: In Progress&amp;hellip;
Project description
I&amp;rsquo;m doing a master&amp;rsquo;s degree at the Intrig electrical engineering group at Unicamp. My goal is to create a digital twin network from the fiber optic networks of the company PadTec from Campinas.
I participated in the application of a gradient descent algorithm on the digital twin. And at the moment I am collecting practical data from the network in order to model the network with real data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Football Simulator</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/fifa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/fifa/</guid>
      <description>Development
Start: 03/2014.
End: Work In Progress&amp;hellip;
Fifa C Game Project description
It started in 2014 as a game made with C programming languages. You could transfer players and play a league mode. Then I also implemented a champions league and copa libertadores simulator where you didn&amp;rsquo;t play as a manager but could simulate this tournaments for many years and see who would be the champions, top goal scorer etc&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Guide</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/ml-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/ml-guide/</guid>
      <description>Development
Start: 10/2022.
End: 06/2023.
Project description (Link to guide)
I made a machine learning guide that includes all stages of its development, main techniques and algorithms developed to date, as well as websites, codes and auxiliary tutorials. It has more than 300 pages, and can help you discover new tools and algorithms that you may never heard of before.
Chapters Include:
Ethics Concepts Pre-Processing Feature Selection Regression Classification Clusters Recommendation Time-Series Neural Networks Reinforcement Learning Ensemble Methods Explainable Models (XAI) AutoML Cost-Sensitive Learning Dimension Reduction Anomaly Detection Model Tuning Evaluation metrics Statistics Model Compression Python and R tools Storytelling with Data AI tools Tutorials, Courses, Code Examples, Books And more&amp;hellip; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MBA Big Data and Business Analytics Projects</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/mba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/mba/</guid>
      <description>Development
Start: 04/2022.
End: 06/2023.
Project description (MBA Page)
Big Data is the term used to describe the vast volume of data that impacts business on a day-to-day basis. The Executive MBA in Business Analytics and Big Data enabled us to analyze business problems and use analytical techniques in this current scenario characterized by complexity, diversity and high volume of digital data.
During the course we learned about:
Analytical ability: To manage and conduct projects involving structured and unstructured databases; Business management: Ability to analyze and identify problems and generate solutions to business problems, based on the practical application of methods; Analytical Problem-Solving: Possessing extensive expertise in data modeling, quantitative analysis, and problem identification/resolution, enabling effective decision-making and driving successful outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT - Temperature module for Weather Station</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/iot/</guid>
      <description>Development
Start: 08/2022.
End: 12/2022.
Project description (Github)
This project was developed for my IoT class - IE321 - Tópicos em Eletrônica II, teached by prof. Fabiano Fruett. The objective of the course was to develop a meteorological station, where each student was responsible for a sensor. I developed the temperature sensor module and helped to create and standardize the code architecture for easy integration with the Raspberry Pi. In addition I worked with 3D printing to integrate the module in the final version of the weather station adding a support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stadium Guesser App</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/stadium-guesser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/stadium-guesser/</guid>
      <description>Development
Start: 07/2022.
End: 08/2022.
Project description
Football guessing game with multiple modes for Android devices developed with Flutter.
The game consists of guessing the stadium of a soccer team, guessing the soccer team that owns the stadium, guessing the club logo or even guessing the location of a soccer team on a map. The game has some modes like normal with 3 lives, no mistake and time trial with 1 minute to hit as much as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Davai - Music Social Network App</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/davai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/davai/</guid>
      <description>Development
Start: 01/2021.
End: 03/2022.
Project Description(Link to PlayStore)
I am the founder with 2 more colleagues of the Davai app. It&amp;rsquo;s a music social network, developed to help people to find friends based on their music taste and help bands to find their audience. It was created in 2021, but the development stopped in march of 2022 after the project members run out of time. The app is still available at Play Store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flutter Apps</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/apps/</guid>
      <description>Star Wars App Development
Start: 02/2022.
End: 02/2022.
Project description (Github)
A mobile app for Android, powered by flutter, which uses an external API to display a list of Star Wars characters and movies. This project was created in under 3 days to participate in a job interview. The user can use it to bookmark their favorite items and access the official Star Wars fan site for recent news. Also, you can customize your avatar&amp;rsquo;s appearance within the app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Supportive App</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/ey-solidario/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/ey-solidario/</guid>
      <description>Development
Start: 12/2020.
End: 12/2020.
Project description
Our group won an EY Business Challenge with this android app idea in december of 2020. The group was composed by 3 members, I was in the developer role. We had 2 weeks to create a business model canvas and create a prototype of our solution for a fake city. The problem was to help the city&amp;rsquo;s trade and economy during the pandemics through a new solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting license plates and pedestrians using YOLO</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/yolo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/yolo/</guid>
      <description>Development
Start: 08/2020.
End: 12/2020.
Project description
YOLO (You Only Look Once) is a real-time object detection algorithm that can detect and identify objects in images and videos. It works by dividing an image into a grid of cells and predicting the object class and bounding box for each cell, using a single convolutional neural network. YOLO is known for its speed and accuracy, making it popular for various computer vision applications such as self-driving cars, surveillance, and robotics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Guitar Pedal</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/guitar-pedal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/guitar-pedal/</guid>
      <description>Development
Start: 07/2020.
End: 10/2020.
Project description
During the pandemics, I bought a guitar and saw that guitar pedals were extremely expensive. However, there were sites on the internet that taught how to create your own project, including ready-made layouts. However I decided to do a simpler version of gain distortion. In three months, I developed the board in Altium, fabricated the board in-house, soldered the components together, and put everything together in a box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drum LED Project</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/drum-led/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/drum-led/</guid>
      <description>Development
Start: 03/2020.
End: 06/2020.
Project description
During the pandemic in 2020, I had the idea and dream of putting LEDs on my battery. After 2 months I finished the project. I mounted an arduino circuit on a board, with selector buttons for the code executed in the microcontroller. The toms and floor use an Arduino-controlled RGB LED, which can be programmed in tune with the music or played in random modes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IST Projects</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/ist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/ist/</guid>
      <description>Development
Start: 08/2019.
End: 02/2020.
Project description
I did an student exchange program in 2019 at Instituto Superior Técnico (IST) in Lisbon, Portugal. I did 4 subjects: Electrical Machines, Machine Learning, Photovoltaic Energy, Image Processing and Vision.
Screenshot
SEITSF project comparing the costs of a photovoltaic project in São Paulo, Brazil and in Pisa, ItalyImage Processing and Vision Project: 3D point reconstruction from a room using kinetic cameraMachine Learning lab example using NLP to detect languagesElectrical Machines lab reportTools</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix Robotics Team Projects</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/phoenix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/phoenix/</guid>
      <description>Development
Start: 03/2017.
End: 06/2019.
The competition
In the robotics team, I participated in the 2017 and 2018 editions of the Winter Challenge. Occurring once a year the Winter Challenge is one of the biggest robotics competitions in all of Latin America. It involves real competitions between robots, such as mortal fights, boxing, or even racing. The competition is organized by RoboCore, a renowned electronics parts manufacturer and seller. Competitions can be automatic robots or radio frequency control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-Racing GPS Telemetry</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/gps-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/gps-plot/</guid>
      <description>Development
Start: 03/2016.
End: 08/2016.
Project description
My first project using python was to create a telemetry system for UNICAMP&amp;rsquo;s e-racing team building electric cars for student competitions. I had to collect the data from several telemetry .csv files collected with GPS data and then get the car performance metric by dividing the track into 3 sections.
I also developed some electric 3d components in SolidWorks and help in the cost report containing all car parts with their quantities, prices and technical drawing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INOVA Unicamp Entrepreneurship Challenge</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/inova-unicamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/inova-unicamp/</guid>
      <description>Development
Start: 03/2021.
End: 06/2021.
Project description
In 2021, I participated in the Unicamp Challenge, organized by the Inova Unicamp Innovation Agency. Anyone over the age of 18 can enroll in teams of 3 to 5 participants in the Unicamp Challenge, an entrepreneurship, technology and innovation competition with prizes of up to R$30,000.
The objective of the competition is to train people interested in entrepreneurship so that they can create new sustainable businesses based on university technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Projects</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/ml/</guid>
      <description>Football - Web Scraper (Github)
Development
Start: 2021.
End: In Progress
Project description
Python files to extract online player data from the database of &amp;ldquo;SoFifa&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;SoccerWiki&amp;rdquo; sites into .csv files, to be used in my Football Manager game.
The file takes data from the sites &amp;ldquo;SoFifa&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;SoccerWiki&amp;rdquo; and using Python&amp;rsquo;s BeautifulSoup looks for Html tags with the necessary information of each player such as name, age, position and potential to save in a &amp;ldquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Projects</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/other-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/other-projects/</guid>
      <description>R markdown Website (Website)
Development
Start: 07/2022.
End: 07/2022.
Project Description
Website development of a R script in Markdown for test purposes.
IBGE insurance brokers (Github)
Development
Start: 04/2022.
End: 04/2022.
Project description
Project to identify the average age of insurance brokers in Brazil, through official data from IBGE surveys using the R language. A friend of mine who worked at Porto Seguros, wanted to start an insurance startup, and asked me to help find out some information about the class of insurance brokers in Brazil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electronics Projects</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/electronics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 20:08:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/electronics/</guid>
      <description>TCC Liceu Development
Start: 09/2014.
End: 11/2014.
Project description
This work aims at the implementation of electronic concepts for the creation of a project that assists the parking of an automotive vehicle. The circuit used will detect obstacles through the use of an ultrasonic sensor, which will emit sound waves that will be reflected by the object. Their return time will determine the distance between the vehicle and the obstacle. If the distance is short, a sound alert will warn the driver, thus avoiding possible accidents and damage to the vehicle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/excel/</guid>
      <description>&amp;mdash; title: &amp;ldquo;Excel Projects&amp;rdquo; hero: /images/projects/electronics.jpg date: 2014-12-10T20:08:28-03:00 description: Excel Projects theme: Toha menu: sidebar: name: Excel Projects identifier: excel parent: projects weight: 500 &amp;mdash; Football Matchs analysis &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; Project Description(Link to Excel Sheet) Sheet with the latest results from the leagues from: Spain, Brazil, England, # Italy, Germany. Then it generates an database to compare the performance of the # clubs. Best Football Players &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; Project Description([Link to Excel Sheet](https://docs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcos14almeida.github.io/mrcmarc/posts/projects/books/</guid>
      <description>Books I have read The Lean Startup: How Today&amp;rsquo;s Entrepreneurs Use Continuous Innovation to Create Radically Successful Businesses by Eric Ries (Link to book)
Leading digital: turning technology into business transformation by George Westerman (Link to book)
Clean Code: A Handbook of Agile Software Craftsmanship by Martin Robert C. (Link to book)
Storytelling with Data: A Data Visualization Guide for Business Professionals by Cole Nussbaumer Knaflic (Link to book)
Data Science for Business: What You Need to Know about Data Mining and Data-Analytic Thinking by Tom Fawcett and Foster Provost (Link to book)</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
